So magic is a very introverted field.
إن السحر مجالٌ محافظ جداً و منغلق على نفسه
While scientists regularly publish their latest research,
بينما العلماء يعملون دوماً على نشر أبحاثهم الأخيرة
we magicians do not like to share our methods and secrets.
لا يقوم السحرة بمشاركة أفكارهم و طرقهم و أسراراهم
That's true even amongst peers.
وهذا أمرٌ واقعي بين الأقران السحرة
But if you look at creative practice as a form of research,
ولكن إن نظرت إلى " الأداء الإبداعي " كنوع من الأبحاث
or art as a form of R&amp;D for humanity,
أو الفنون أو كنوع من البحث والتطوير للبشرية
then how could a cyber illusionist like myself
كيف إذا يمكن لساحر " إلكتروني " مثل
share his research?
أن يشارك أبحاثه ؟
Now my own speciality is combining digital technology and magic.
إن تخصصي الحقيقي هو دمج التكنولوجيا والسحر " ألعاب الخفة "
And about three years ago,
ومنذ نحو 3 أعوام
I started an exercise
بدأت أطبق
in openness and inclusiveness
الإنفتاح والشمولية
by reaching out into the open-source software community
عن طريق الخوض في مجتمع برامج المصادر المفتوحة
to create new digital tools for magic --
من اجل ان اصنع أدوات جديدة من أجل ألعاب الخفة
tools that could eventually be shared with other artists
أدوات يمكن في نهاية المطاف أن أتشارك بها مع فنانين آخرين
to start them off further on in the process
من أجل أن يستمروا لاحقاً على نفس الخطى والمنوال
and to get them to the poetry faster.
ومن أجل دمجهم في النسق بسرعة أكبر
Today, I'd like to show you something which came out of these collaborations.
واليوم أريد أن أريكم شيئاً من نتاج ذلك التعاون و الدمج بين عالم السحر و التقنية
It's an augmented reality
إنه " واقعٌ معزز "
projection tracking and mapping system,
خليط بين نظام إسقاط .. و نظام تعقب
or a digital storytelling tool.
أو ما يمكن تسميته " قاص روائي إلكتروني "
Could we bring down the lights please? Thank you.
هلا قمتم بخفض الإضاءة من فضلكم ؟ شكراً
So let's give this a try.
دعونا نحاول هذا الأمر
And I'm going to use it
سوف أحاول أن أستخدم هذه
to give you my take
من أجل أن أريكم مأخذي
on the stuff of life.
عن أمور الحياة
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
(Music)
(موسيقى)
Terribly sorry. I forgot the floor.
عُذراً .. لقد نسيت رسم الأرضية
Wake up.
إستيقظ
Hey.
هيا
(Music)
(موسيقى)
Please.
من فضلك
Come on.
هيا
Ah, sorry about that.
آه .. أسف لهذا
Forgot this.
تجاهل الأمر
(Music)
(موسيقى)
Give it another try.
حاول مرة أخرى
Okay.
حسناً
He figured out the system.
لقد فطن نظام الإضاءة
(Music)
(موسيقى)
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
(Music)
(موسيقى)
Uh oh.
آه .. هاا
All right. Let's try this.
حسناً .. لنجرب هذا
Come on.
هيا
(Music)
(موسيقى)
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Hey.
هيا
(Music)
(موسيقى)
You heard her, go ahead.
لقد سمعتها .. تقدم
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Bye-bye.
وداعاً .. وداعاً